Knight, Max; Papers ger050
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Max Knight Papers1909-1993
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Knight, Max
ger050
4 cubic ft.
The bulk of the collection consists of the writings of the co-authors Max Knight (Max Eugen Kühnel) and Joseph Fabry (Joseph Epstein), who wrote and published jointly from 1933 to 1993 under the pseudonym of Peter Fabrizius. The duo wrote and published short stories, poetry and drama in German in their native Austria until 1938, when both were forced to flee the Hitler regime. After 1938, the authors reunited in the United States (San Francisco) and continued to publish under the joint pseudonym in both English and German. Although many of the earlier short stories were translated, the duo gradually changed to essayistic writing and translation of German poetry and verse into English. Although the bulk of the published writings appeared under the Peter Fabrizius pen name, Knight and Fabry also published individually under their own names, as well as jointly under various other pseudonyms, including: Charlotte Ellert, Peter Joe Fabry, Peter Förster, Peter Foster, Fregoli, Paul Fridolin, Ernst Friese, Hugh Gosser, Stephan Hanke, Dr. Josef Hans, J. Hinkel, Myra (Mia) Schütz and Oliver Twin.
Biographical Sketch
Max Knight was born Max Kühnel on June 8, 1909 to Bernhard and Margarethe Hoffer Kühnel in Pilsen, Austria (now The Czech Republic). He led a very protected and comfortable childhood, his father having attained a secure position as vice president of the Wiener Bankverein. Although of Jewish descent, the Kühnels were not practicing Jews, nor did they observe Jewish traditions or holidays. Max received his classical education, including Latin and Greek studies, history, social sciences, physical sciences and mathematics at the Gymnasium, while receiving private tutoring in English and French along with piano, gymnastics, fencing, dancing, literature and art history.
After graduating from the gymnasium, and although he had strongly expressed his wish to become a writer, Max was convinced by his parents to attend the University of Vienna to pursue law, a more practical career, in the event his writing career was not successful enough to earn him a living. In 1931, while attending a university study seminar, Max first made the acquaintance of Joseph Epstein (later Joseph Fabry), who was to become the other half of the writing duo known as Peter Fabrizius. This collaboration and friendship, which spanned a period of fifty years and occasionally published under other pseudonyms as well (Brandy von Brandenburg, Oliver Twin), began in Austria, continued through their separate flights from the Nazis in Austria, reunited for a brief time in London, and finally permanently reunited in Berkeley, California.
The short stories and poems published under the name of Peter Fabrizius (the most popular pen name of Max Kühnel and Joseph Epstein) were often a collaborative effort, written by one, edited by the other, and rewritten again by the first; other pieces were written solely by one member of the duo. In all cases, however, publication appeared under the joint name of Peter Fabrizius, with neither party claiming sole ownership of the piece. For this reason, with the exception of the few pieces that appeared under Max Kühnel or Joseph Epstein, it is nearly impossible to discern which member of the duo was responsible for actually penning a certain piece. This pattern continued into the 1960s, until separate careers and interests produced articles and publications under the individual (anglicized) names of Max Knight and Joseph Fabry. The friendship continued and one last Fabrizius collaboration was realized in 1988 with the publication of their "duography" entitled One and One Make Three: Story of a Friendship.
Max Kühnel fled Austria on March 11, 1938, the same day Kurt Schuschnigg resigned as Chancellor of Austria, leaving the way free for the country's annexation by Hitler. Max managed to reach England, procured a job at the Jewish Spectator, and arranged for his parents to join him in November. Early in 1940, Max realized that England might soon suffer the fate of France and began preparations to immigrate to the U.S. The wait would be nearly a year, but since he feared waiting in London, he applied for travel to the only port that accepted refugees without visas, Shanghai, China. On August 10, 1940 Max left London on a ship bound for Halifax, Canada, crossing Canada to Vancouver by train, and finally sailing to Shanghai, arriving on October 5. Kühnel remained in Shanghai, working as an English teacher and a staff member on the North China Daily News, until May of 1941, when with the help of his lifelong friend, he obtained a visa for the U.S.
On May 2, 1941, Max Kühnel boarded a ship bound for Seattle, Washington. Eleven days later, under the advice of friend Joseph Epstein (now known as Joseph Fabry), Max debarked in Seattle as Max Knight. Several months later, the two writers were reunited in San Francisco.
Max Knight's and Joseph Fabry's careers in the U.S. took different paths. Both men married, Joe early in 1941, Max in mid-1942. Joe became an editor for Agricultural Information, later joined the Unitarian Church, and was introduced to the works of Viktor Frankl, becoming the leading exponent of Frankl's teachings in the Untied States. Max returned to school, received his Ph.D. in Political Science at the University of California, Berkeley, and eventually became Editor of the University of California Press, a position he kept until his retirement in 1976. His literary path turned to the art of translation, translating from German into English plays by Bertolt Brecht, poems by Christian Morgenstern, correspondence of Richard Strauss and Stefan Zweig, as well as works by Gottfried Benn, Johann Nestroy, and the law theory of his former Austrian law instructor, Hans Kelsen. He also translated Ogden Nash from English into German, and received Austria's Goldenes Ehrenzeichen für Verdienste um die Republik Österreich (Golden Honor Award) for his translations of Karl Kraus and Johann Nestroy.
Max Knight died at the age of 84 on August 31, 1993 at his home in Berkeley, California from complications which developed after a heart bypass operation in February of the same year. He was survived by his wife, Charlotte, two sons, Anthony and Martin, and his life-long friend and collaborator, Joseph Fabry.
Chronology of Events:
1909 June 8, born in Pilsen, Austria (now The Czech Republic) to Bernhard and Margaret (née Hoffer) Kühnel.
1915-1921 Attended Volkschule.
1921-1928 Attended the classical Gymnasium in Vienna.
1928-1933 Attended the University of Vienna to study law.
1931 First made the acquaintance of Joseph Epstein (later Joseph Fabry) in a law seminar.
1931-1938 Wrote short stories and poetry (nearly 200 pieces) for Austrian and German literary journals, together with Joseph Epstein under the pen name of Peter Fabrizius; wrote regularly for the Neues Wiener Tagblatt.
1933 Received the Doctor of Law degree from the University of Vienna.
1933-1935 Worked as a law clerk in Vienna.
1937 Became a free-lance writer for the Neues Wiener Tagblatt; Oct.-Dec., went to London in order to sell the Fabrizius stories to British newspapers.
1938 March 10, received a job as a feature editor for the Neues Wiener Tagblatt; March 11, left Austria for England, the same day that Kurt Schuschnigg resigned as Chancellor of Austria.
1938-1940 Lived in London, writing short stories and feature articles for the Daily Herald and other British papers, literary journals; received a position at the Jewish Chronicle, reading and summarizing articles from Nazi newspapers.
1939 March 22, reuniting of Peter Fabrizius in London.
1940-1941 Lived in Shanghai; news editor for the North China Daily News.
1941 Immigration to the United States; arrived in Seattle, Washington on May 13.
1942 Attended the University of California, Berkeley as a graduate student in Oriental languages; married Charlotte Lowes of Toronto, Canada.
1943 Became naturalized American citizen.
1943-1945 Became a scriptwriter and news analyst in the Chinese Section of the U.S. Office of War Information.
1945-1947 Became Financial Editor of the San Francisco Daily Commercial News.
1947 Birth of son, Anthony.
1947-1948 Became a Lecturer in International Relations at the San Francisco Unified School District.
1949-1950 University of California, Berkeley Ph.D. program in Political Science/International Relations as a Research Assistant; became Deputy Executive Secretary of RADIR (Revolution and Development of International Relations, a Carnegie project) at the Hoover Institution, Stanford.
1951-1976 Principal Editor of the University of California Press.
1951 Birth of son, Martin.
1967-1993 Participation in the University of California Extension, Editorial Workshop.
1976 Retirement from the University of California Press.
1976-1993 Freelance editor, various publishers and university presses.
1986 Received the Golden Honor Award for his translations of Karl Kraus and Johann Nestroy from German into English from the Austrian government (Goldenes Ehrenzeichen für Verdienste um die Republik Österreich).
1993 Aug. 31, died at the age of 84 at home in Berkeley, California.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of the collection consists of the writings of the co-authors Max Knight (Max Eugen Kühnel) and Joseph Fabry (Joseph Epstein), who wrote and published jointly from 1933 to 1993 under the pseudonym of Peter Fabrizius. The duo wrote and published short stories, poetry and drama in German in their native Austria until 1938, when both were forced to flee the Hitler regime. After 1938, the authors reunited in the United States (San Francisco) and continued to publish under the joint pseudonym in both English and German. Although many of the earlier short stories were translated, the duo gradually changed to essayistic writing and translation of German poetry and verse into English. Although the bulk of the published writings appeared under the Peter Fabrizius pen name, Knight and Fabry also published individually under their own names, as well as jointly under various other pseudonyms, including: Charlotte Ellert, Peter Joe Fabry, Peter Förster, Peter Foster, Fregoli, Paul Fridolin, Ernst Friese, Hugh Gosser, Stephan Hanke, Dr. Josef Hans, J. Hinkel, Myra (Mia) Schütz and Oliver Twin.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
.
Series arrangement statement: SUNY will complete.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the family of Max Knight in 1993.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Literature; Exiles -- Germany.; German literature -- Translations into English.; Knight, Max.; Fabrizius, Peter.
- Autobiographical and biographical materials, 1909-1991; 1; 13 file folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains a complete life story and family history of the Kühnel/Knight family, illustrated with old photographs, documents, and correspondence. Also included in this series are short biographical statements and publications lists.
  - Biographical statements, clippings, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 2)
  - Autobiography, vol. I, beginning with: "Roots. From Papa's birth to honeymoon trip, 1876-1908", Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 3-4)
  - Autobiography, vol. II, beginning with: "The Trip Back. Shanghai to Seattle. The actual diary translated from the German). May 1 to May 19, 1941", Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 5-7)
  - Autobiography, Appendixes, Undated; originals (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 8-9)
  - Autobiography, Appendixes, Undated; photocopies (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 10)
  - Autobiography, Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 11)
  - "Ruminations". Opinions on various topics, typed, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 12)
  - Interview, 1985 October 16 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 13)
  - Holocaust Oral History Interview by Peggy Koster, 1991 February 28 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and biographical materials), Folder 14)
- Correspondence files, 1940-1992; 2; 109 file folders
  This series contains correspondence with colleagues, clients of translations, and publishers. Noteworthy is the correspondence between Knight and co-author Joseph Fabry from 1940-1941, when Knight was in Shanghai and Fabry was already in the U.S. Also represented in the correspondence are: Jacques Barzun, Stefan Brecht (son of Bertolt Brecht), Hans Kelsen, illustrator Wolfgang Lederer, Edward Lowinsky, Thornton Wilder and Hans Zeisl.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - A -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 15)
  - American Translators Association, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 16)
  - B -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 17)
  - Barbary, George F., 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 18)
  - Barry de Longchamp, Nicole, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 18)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 19)
  - Bateson, John, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 19)
  - Bay Area Poets' Coalition, 1992 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 20)
  - Bendix, Reinhard, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 20)
  - Bienenfeld, Franz Rudolf, 1959 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 20)
  - Brecht, Stefan S., 1967; 1968; 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 21)
  - Brent, Bern, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 22)
  - Briar, Anni, 1978-1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 23)
  - Brown, Howard M., 1975-1979; 1987 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 24)
  - Brunn, George & Ruth, 1980-1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 25)
  - Bundesversicherungsamt für Angestellte, 1980-1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 25)
  - Buxbaum, Richard, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 26)
  - C - D -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 27)
  - Case, Bertha, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 28)
  - Choi, Dai-Kwon, 1983; 1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 28)
  - Cranston, Alan (Senator), 1976-1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 29)
  - Davis, Col. Wilbur E., 1975-1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 30)
  - DeBecker, Eva & Hans, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 31)
  - Dehlinger, Peter, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 31)
  - Dietrich, Karl E., 1972 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 31)
  - Dreyfus, George, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 31)
  - E - F -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 32)
  - Ehrenzweig, Albert A. (family), 1975-1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 33)
  - Eis, Egon, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 33)
  - Elbogen, Paul, 1976; 1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 33)
  - Euben, Peter, 1982-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 34)
  - Fabry, Joseph & Judy, 1940-1941; 1968-1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 35)
  - Feder, Maria K. (daughter of Hans Kelsen), 1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 36)
  - Feest, Johannes, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 36)
  - Felstiner, John, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 36)
  - Fischer, Helmut, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 36)
  - Frank, Peter R., 1980-1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 37)
  - Freais, William, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 38)
  - Free, Margaret (Estate of), 1975-1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 38)
  - Frieders, George, 1982-1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 39)
  - Frieders, Hans, 1982-1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 39)
  - Friesen, Gerhard, 1981-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 40)
  - Fromm, Hanna, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 40)
  - G - H -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 41)
  - Garcia, Max & Patricia, 1976-1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 42)
  - George, Manfred, 1965 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 43)
  - Göbl, Robert, 1977-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 43)
  - Goetzl, Franz, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 44)
  - Gotoda, Teruo, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 44)
  - Gratum, George, 1971; 1977-1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 45)
  - Greer, Lucy R., 1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 46)
  - Groszmann, Karl & Eleanor, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 46)
  - Haag, John, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 47)
  - Hanna, Warren L., 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 47)
  - Havrda, Jiri, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 47)
  - Hillebrand, Beate, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 47)
  - J - K -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 48)
  - Jaroschy, François, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 49)
  - Jeffery, Brian, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 49)
  - Kalmer, Erica, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 50)
  - Kann, Robert A., 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 50)
  - Kauders, Friedel, 1976-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 50)
  - Knepler, Walter, 1978-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 51)
  - Knight, Anthony (son), 1975-1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 52)
  - Knight, Charlotte (wife), 1973-1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 53)
  - Knight, Martin (son), 1975-1981 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 54)
  - Kriegel, Diana, 1983-1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 55)
  - Kühnel, Margaret (Muschi, mother), 1975-1976 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 56)
  - L - M -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 57)
  - Lederer, Wolfgang, 1976-1982 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 58)
  - Libby, Peter, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 58)
  - Loewald, Klaus, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 59)
  - Lovy, Charles W. (memorial service), 1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 59)
  - Lowinsky, Edward, 1974-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 60)
  - MacLeod, Celeste, 1978-1980 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 61)
  - Manheim, Ralph, 1968 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 62)
  - Marshall, Eugene, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 63)
  - Matzner, Hans L., 1983-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 63)
  - Mautner, Franz, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 63)
  - McClung, William J. (University of California Press), 1978-1984 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 64)
  - Mitterwallner, Maria, 1972-1975 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 65)
  - Modell, Sol, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 65)
  - Moody, Tom & Joan, 1981-1983 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 66)
  - Musjenko, Krista & Franzi, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 66)
  - N - R -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 1)
  - Nelson, Lois Patricia (Pat), 1983-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 2)
  - Oldberg, Ingmar, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 2)
  - Oppenheim, Lilly, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 2)
  - Petris, Nicholas (Senator), 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 3)
  - Popper-Portnow, Alice (Lisl Hirschfeld), 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 3)
  - Propper de Callejon', Felipe, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 3)
  - Rabel(-Haymann), Lili, 1976-1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 4)
  - Rieselfreudig, Beate, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 4)
  - Rosenberg, Marvin, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 4)
  - Ross, Karl, 1956-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 5)
  - Rotenberg, Stella, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 5)
  - S -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 6)
  - Sachs, Emmy, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 7)
  - Schauer, Elisabeth (Sissy) & Johannes, 1982-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 7)
  - Schwarz, Gerhart, 1976; 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 8)
  - Schwarz, Kurt & Erna, 1978-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 8)
  - Schwarz, Patricia, 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 9)
  - Seabury, Paul, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 9)
  - Service, John (Jack), 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 9)
  - Shelley, Lore, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 10)
  - Sloss, Louis, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 10)
  - Smelser, Neil J., 1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 10)
  - Stachenfeld, Avi & Shirley Nachmann, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 10)
  - Starck-Pauly, Ilse, 1975-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 11)
  - Steiner, Ruth & Paul, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 12)
  - Stremayr, Trude & Heinz, 1975-1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 12)
  - Swann, Lucy, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 13)
  - Szilard, Gertrude Weiss, 1964; 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 13)
  - T - Z -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 14)
  - Teltscher, Erwin S., 1990 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 15)
  - Torberg, Friedrich, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 16)
  - Tucholsky, Kurt. Transcripts of letters to Stefan Zweig, 1935 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 16)
  - University of California, Berkeley. General correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 17)
  - Veith, Ilza, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 18)
  - Vrba, Else, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 18)
  - Weil, Konrad, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 18)
  - Western Humor and Irony Membership (WHIM), 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 19)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1965-1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 20)
  - Wilson, Adrian, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 21)
  - Wyatt, Frederick, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 21)
  - Zeisel, Hans, 1977-1984 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 22)
  - Zimmerman, Sangwan, 1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 23)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 2.128
    Including contracts.
    - Abele Arts Corporation (Jane Cohen), 1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 24)
    - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP), 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 25)
    - Appleton-Century Crofts, 1950; 1956 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 26)
    - Benmir Books, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 27)
    - bj books (Boris Bresler), 1983 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 28)
    - Buchhandlung Franz Deuticke (Hans Kelsen), 1962; 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 29)
    - Caedman Records, Inc., 1969-1970 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 30)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 31)
    - Engendra Press Ltd., 1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 32)